Name: Basanta Shrestha

Address: Unit 6/44 Donald Street, St Marys, 5042, SA

**Phone**: 0410168848

Linked in: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/basanta-shrestha-31b0bb192">www.linkedin.com/in/basanta-shrestha-31b0bb192</a>

Email: 13asanta.shrestha@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Diligent web developer with a Bachelor's qualification in Computer Science and Information Technology, and expecting to enhance my expert involvement in an IT organization specializing in web development. Armed with a profound awareness of other's expectations and having extremely significant levels of eagerness to give my 110% for any undertaking.

## **Core Qualifications:**

• Languages: HTML, CSS, Python, JQuery and JavaScript

• Frameworks: Bootstrap, Django

• Designing tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Microsoft visio

• Documentation: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint

### **Professional Qualifications:**

• A certified Microsoft Office Specialist of the year 2015

### **Experience:**

• IT Operator (06/2019-11/2020) Gateway Payment Service Pvt. Ltd Duties:

- o Designed and maintained company website.
- o Smoothly operated the participants on-boarding system, managed new users and thoroughly checked the security of data by restricting permissions.
- Designed flow chart, class diagnosis and documents for proper understanding payment service provider functions.
- Educating new staff about the PCI DSS standards, 3D secure method and antifraud management through presentation.
- Dealing with various clients from banks, IT solution companies and other relatable sectors.

• Web Designer (01/2018-06/2019)

Thakur International and Investment Pvt. Ltd.

#### **Duties:**

- o Establish the purpose of the website based upon its target audience
- o Identify the type of content the site will host
- o Give guidance on layout, colours and styles
- o Demonstrating designing skills with photoshop and illustrator
- o Managing a team and meeting the deadline of the project
- o Handling client by prioritizing their requirements
- Digital Marketing (06/2017-07/2018) DeliBird Apparel Line (Own Startup)
- Independent tutor (2013-2016)

### **Education:**

- Bachelors of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology (B.Sc. CSIT)
  Prime College (2014-2018)
- Higher Secondary Course in Science Prime College (2012-2014)

# **Personal Projects:**

- Online Car Rental System Application (09/2018-02/2019)
- Management Information System (05/2016-07/2016)

## **Skills:**

- Excellent Communication Skill
- Proper Team Management Skill
- Analytical and Time Management Skill
- Up-to-date with the advancement in the industry
- Always focused in designing unique user experience and interface

#### Languages:

• English: Bilingual Proficiency

• Nepali: Native Proficiency

• Hindi: Professional Proficiency

• Japanese: Elementary Proficiency

### **Reference:**

Ujwal Khadgi

**Network Administrator Level 2** 

**Uniti Wireless** 

0435089194

**Shahadev Basnet** 

**Branch Manager** 

Mega Bank Nepal Limited

9851201283

**Pratik Pradhan** 

**Chief Information Officer** 

**Gateway Payment Service Pvt. Ltd.** 

9851365100